[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Good, so this is our data set.
很好，所以这是我们的数据
Then the next step for us is to create a recommender system.
那我们下一步要创建一个推荐系统
So, here we go.
那么我们开始吧
Let's go ahead and create a song recommender.
让我们马上开始搭建一个歌曲推荐系统
So as usual, we're gonna start by doing a train test split.
照例，我们一开始要划分训练数据和测试数据
So when I take the train_data, the data is splitted into train and test data.
因此我们定义train_data时 数据已经被分成了训练数据和测试数据
And we do that by taking the song data,
而划分的方法是将音乐数据
we're going to do a random split on this data set of 80% for
随机地划分开来，其中训练数据占80%
training, 20% for testing.
测试数据占20%
And again when we're gonna set this to zero, so
还有 别忘了把这个量归零
that if you do this at home you'll get the exact same answers I got.
这样你在家自己计算的时候就会得到完全一样的结果了
Okay, we've done that split.
好了 我们完成了划分
And now we're ready to train some recommender models.
我们现在准备好要训练一些推荐器的模型了
So just following the lecture a little bit that Emily gave,
因此只需要按照艾米丽之前讲到的
the first recommender model that we're gonna
我们第一个训练的推荐器模型是
train is a simple popularity-based recommender.
一个简单的基于流行程度的推荐系统
So this is what many websites do, for example, when they
这是很多网站用到的 比如说 当他们说
say here are the most email stories or this is the most purchased products,
这是最多邮件转发的故事或者这是购买量最大的产品，
this is what's most popular, and most common hashtags on Twitter today.
或者这是今天推特上最流行最常用的标签
Not a particularly great model, but it's used a lot.
这并不是一个特别好的模型 但是它非常常用
So, let's train our famous popularity model.
好的 让我们来训练这个著名的基于流行度的模型吧
I'm gonna call it popularity_model.
我把它命名为popularity_model
And all I have to do now is call graphlab.popularity_recommender.
我现在只需要调用graphlab.popularity_recommender
So this is a particular recommender.
这是一个专有的推荐系统
And I tried create next to it, and
我尝试在它下面调用create 如果
as you remember, create is the verb here that actually creates the recommender.
你还记得的话 create在这里是用来创建推荐系统的动词
And, I'm gonna give it my training data as input.
然后 我将把我的训练数据作为输入量
And this model takes a little bit of information.
这个模型会读入一些信息
So let me just walk you through it.
那么让我来一步步展示给你看
You have to say what column is the user_id in the dataset.
你需要指出数据库中的那一列是用户名
So in our case that column is called just user_id.
在我们这个例子中那一列就叫做user_id
User_id.
用户名
Then we need to say what column is the item_id.
接着我们需要指明条目名
So the item_id is, in our case the product, so users and products.
而条目名 或者我们例子中的产品名 也就是用户和产品
But we don't have exactly a product in our item.
但是我们的条目并不是严格意义上的产品
Our item here is songs.
这里我们的条目是歌曲
So item_id is equal to song, and now when I hit Enter, it creates,
因此条目名等于歌曲名 那我现在按回车 它会很快创建
and it was very quick, created a simple popularity based recommender system.
一个简单的基于流行度的推荐系统
So let's just make some predictions.
现在让我们来做预测
So, in our next step, we're going to use,
那下一步我们用，
I'll just scroll down a little bit.
让我把鼠标向下滚动一下
Use the popularity model to
我们用流行度模型来
make some predictions.
做一些预测
So for example let's take this popularity model and
比如说我们用这个流行度模型来
let's ask it to recommend for a particular user.
对一个特定用户进行推荐
So I'm gonna recommend some songs this particular user like.
那么我要推荐一些这个用户喜欢的歌曲
So, this recommender function takes a list of users and
因此 这个推荐器函数会提取一些用户
we're just gonna give one to the list right now.
而我们现在就给它提供其中一个用户
And if you remember, we had that users array.
如果你记得的话 我们有一个用户列表
I'm just gonna give you the first person in that users array and execute.
我就把那个用户列表的第一个人输入函数并运行
So what do you recommend for this person?
那么你会给这个人推荐什么呢
A song by Harmonia, a song by Bjork, King of Leon and so on.
一首Harmonia的歌 一首比约克的 一首里昂王朝的，等等
Now look at this very carefully.
那么现在仔细看一下这个结果
Right here Yoakam this what's being recommended by User zero.
这里的约卡姆是推荐给零号用户的
Now let's see what this model recommends for User one.
现在我们看看这个模型给一号用户推荐的是什么
So again we're gonna take popularity model and
我们再用这个流行度模型
I'm gonna call recommend and again, I'm gonna give it a list of users.
我再调用一次这个推荐系统，给它一组用户
But instead of giving me user zero, I'm gonna give it user one.
这一次 我不用零号用户 而是用一号用户
Now before I click Enter here, Shift+Enter, stop and think.
现在在我按回车之前 先停下来想一想
What am I gonna get back out of popularity model?
我从这个流行度模型中会得到什么结果呢？
Well, everybody gets recommended exactly the same things.
嗯 每个人都会被推荐完全一样的东西。
Because we just recommended the most popular items.
因为我们只是推荐了最流行的歌曲
So this person also gets recommended Harmonia, Bjork, Dwight Yoakam,
因此这个人也会被推荐Harmonia 比约克 德怀特约卡姆
King of Leon, so basically, not that exciting.
里昂王朝 基本上 这并不很有趣
Everybody gets recommended the same things.
因为所有人都得到了相同的推荐
This is a problem with this model.
这是这个模型的一个问题
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community